Hello friends, you are watching your channel
Share Ba Ayush and friends,
in this video we will talk about the listing of ICICI Pidential AMC IPO.
Friends,
ICICI Pidential AMC is going to be listed tomorrow,
so what kind of listing will we get to see,
what are the expectations of the listing,
along with the listing, friends, in this video
I will also share two brokerage reports with you,
yes the IPO has not been listed yet,
but the reports of two brokers have
also come and their targets have been seen coming.
So this
will be a very interesting video for you
because in this we will not
only understand the listing strategy but will also understand
what the brokerages are saying?  Is this
company long term?  Meaning whether
the portfolio is a pick or not.  So you
guys must watch the entire video.  But
before that I have a small request from you.
If you have visited the channel for the first time, then
first of all you must subscribe to the channel
and if you
like the video after watching it completely, then please like it.
So friends, congratulations to all those who got allotment of ICICI Pencal AMC.
You have got one share for Rs 2165.
You would have received six shares.  If
you invested in retail, if you invested in HAI,
you got 96 shares.  Now
friends, whenever an IPO comes, we
see what type of IPO it was?
Meaning it was a fresh issue, there was an offer for sale.  What
was it?  So friends, this IPO was a complete
OFS worth Rs 10,602 crore.  First of all,
how much is the entire OFS and that too of such a big size?  10,602 crore.  This in
itself means that the size of the issue was quite big, friends.
Now friends, OFS is considered a little
negative because the
reason given behind it is that OFS is coming.
Meaning the company definitely does not need money.  The
promoters of the company are
seen selling their shares.  Definitely they
would want it to sell at a good high price.
So this is a slightly negative view.
But friends,
you know that recently many such OFS have come out.
It has created tremendous wealth for
investors.  So I think this IPO was also
similar whose valuation was
not kept very high.  Of course, there was a
complete OFS but the valuation was
kept correct.  The second thing that gets the most
attention is
subscription.  Now subscription guys
if you look at how great it turned out.
Remember, the QIB
category was seen subscribing to this IPO almost 124 times.
Remember which means ₹5 lakh crore in this IPO by QIB.  are
inserted altogether.  That means overall QIB has
invested a lot of money in this IPO.  Two and a half lakh crores.  Remember,
it has already come at number three among the three IPOs with maximum investment by QIBs.
First, friends,
remember you get to see LG.  Second is
Bajaj Housing Finance and third,
remember that has already been done, ICICI Piden.
Apart from this, HI category was subscribed 22 times.
Retail category was subscribed two and a half times, sorry
share holder category almost friends, if you
see, it was subscribed 9.75 times.
Overall, the company appears to have received around ₹3 lakh crore.
Now keep this in mind that
if an IPO is getting so much money then one
thing is clear that the demand for that IPO was
very high.  So the second point is that the
company ticks the subscription very well.
Reason being because
this IPO was seen getting a very good response.
Now some more things
about the company so that you can understand the long term view of the company.
Look,
first of all keep this in mind that ICICI
promc is the most profitable
AMC in India.  Yes, remember that the
company earns the most profit and the company gets to see the
profit market share of the overall 20% industry.  The
market dominance is such
that the company is the largest AMC in
India by active equity, right?
I am talking about UM and
is the second largest overall, meaning on the first place you get to
see SBI AMC and its
overall total asset under management is Rs
10 lakh crore, on the second place you get to
see 56%, remember
their asset under management is within high
margin equity and equity oriented
schemes.  So keep this in mind.  The
company also benefits from this as
it is definitely able to earn higher margins.
Apart from this, the customer loyalty of the company is
so great that
remember, you get to see overall 1.5 crore customers of the company
and remember, 92% of them are
customers with systematic transactions
who are seen lasting you for at least more than 5 years.
Apart from this, if
you look at the parent age, you can see ICICI Bank and
Prudential AMC, sorry, of Prudential Group.
So there is no
doubt that
you get to see a very wonderful parentage company.
Apart from this, their
distribution power is very strong.  There
are 1.1 lakh plus distributors.  There
are 67 partner banks.  So what this shows is
that friends, how the company has
established itself is very important.
So why is it important to know all this
?  Because keep this in mind that ICICI
Approved MC is a pure play.
Friends, as the Indian stock market grows, this
company will also be seen doing well.  And
as people join mutual funds, the
company will definitely see profits
and remember ICICI, while
comparing it, keep this in mind that do
not compare it with small AMCs, if you have to compare it then
definitely its best
peer right now which is listed is HDFC AMC,
compare it with that, the rest of the companies are very small in comparison to all
these, you will have to keep one thing in mind,
right now as I said
some brokerage reports have already come on this,
what is their target, first I will
show you that, so friends, we saw a coverage coming from
Equirus Securities.
Keep this in mind.  Aquarus
Securities released its first research
report on this.  So, friends,
look at their coverage and what was said in the coverage
?  Friends in the coverage Euros Securities
said that ICICI PE AMC is an equity
powerhouse.  PMS is the engine and
industry leading profitability
of the company and initiate with long.
He has advised to stay inside it for a long time.  The
current market price is around Rs
2165.  But the target
price given by them is ₹2900 by March
2027.  Meaning, according to them,
they feel that an upside of about 34% should be seen in
this company.  So you see
what target has been given in the report of Equivalence Securities.  He
clearly said that the Indian mutual fund
industry has shown consistent robust growth.  The
Revenue
EBITDA paid CAGR has been excellent over the last 5 years.  The
industry's pad has been
seen crossing approximately ₹10 billion within F25, which is approximately
23% (23 basis points).  Remember the
average of qA.  Apart from this, ICI Potential
AMC, which leads the industry in
terms of profitability and has the highest
PAT market share of 17.4% in FY25,
so keep this in mind that Accurate
Securities has said that this is a very big report, if you
read it, it will take a lot of time,
but no doubt what has been said clearly from their side is
that you should be long in the company, that is, you should remain long
and they feel that the target of ₹2900 should be
achieved here by March 27. The
second report, friends, has been seen coming from
PL Capital, that is, Prabhu Liladhar
Capital. Friends, the
target has been given by them on the company
and if you
see the target, you will say wow. So look, the
first thing here is the rating of
buy, which means there is a buy opinion from their side.
They have said that the market price is
2165, but our target price
is ₹3000, yes ₹3000.  Remember,
Prabhudas Lilladher Capital, PL Capital has come up with a
target,
they have given a buy rating and
according to them the value has been done
at 38 times on September 27, ah core EPS
target price of Rs 3000 has been given.
He said that we are optimistic about
the business prospects given.  Firstly, it is the
strong performance of the parentage that
drives the overall performance of the company with the highest
net equity flow market share of around
17.5% in 8 months within F26 and
among AMCs this was clearly stated.  Secondly,
it has superior equity yields of 67
basis points due to lowest
distributor payout.  So these overall
positive points were made by them.
But one thing is clear that one brokerage has
given a target of Rs 2900 and another brokerage has
given a target of Rs 3000.  Meaning,
if you look from both sides, then
both these brokerages see an upside of more than 35%.
So these are the broker reports
that I am sharing with you.  But
now let's come to where I think the
list might be tomorrow.  So friends,
you know that the price band is 2165.
If you look at the revenue of the company, it was
around ₹4980 crore in FY25
with a profit of ₹2650 crore.  Now
look at the EMC business itself, it is amazing.
The way profitability
is maintained, margins are maintained.  The
company has brought its IPO at a pricing of Rs 33.  If
you look at the return on equity, it is 82.8% and the
return on net worth is 82.8%, both are equal,
which is strong in itself.  According to me
friends, this company will be seen getting listed tomorrow
between Rs 2650 to Rs 700.  According to me,
listing can be seen around 2650 to 2700.  It might
even open up above it.  It's
not a big deal.  Because we have seen that currently
most of the money that comes into IPOs is
through QIBs, they seem to be doing very well.  They seem to be
doing much better than what is estimated.
Already, as far as we can say, the grey market
is running, according to me, it will be
seen getting listed much higher than that.  Therefore, according to me,
listing can be seen between ₹2650 and ₹2700.
And the profit that
you can see is around ₹3200
on a higher side.  If the list is above this then
definitely I will be the most x
a happiest person right tomorrow.  But
according to me friends, yes, this can be done by
estimating the listing.  I think this is
a company that you
can keep as a part of your portfolio
over a long term.  I don't think there is
any issue within the company.  As I
said friends, as the Indian equity
market grows, remember this is its pure play.
Right?  They seem to be getting direct benefit from it.
So this is one of the biggest
benefits with this company.  And so
I think a good listing here can be
expected with certainty.
Rest of you friends, tell me
what do you think?  Will the
list be above 2700 tomorrow or below 2600, tell us
in the comment section.  That's all there was in this video.
Thank you friends for watching this
video.